The ball in the hole
球在洞里
School is over.  Li Ming and Han Fei are going back home.
放学后  李明和韩菲正要回家
Near the school gate they see a little boy.  He is crying.
在学校大门附近看见一个小男孩正在哭
They go up to him and ask, “What’s wrong with you?”
他们走上前问  你怎么了
The boy points to a hole in the ground and says,
小男孩指着地上的洞说
“My ball is in the hole and I can’t get it out.  Can you help me?”
我的球掉进洞里了  我拿不出来  你们能帮我吗
“Don’t worry,” says Li Ming. “We can help you.”
别担心  李明说  我们可以帮你
They look into the hole and try to take the ball out with their hands,
他们向洞里看  试着用手把球拿出来
but they can’t because the hole is too deep.
但是因为洞太深了他们做不到
They think and think.  Then Li Ming has an idea.
他们想了又想  李明有了个主意
“We can use water,” he says.
我们可以用水  他说。
“Oh, yes!  That’s a good idea,” Han Fei says.
对呀  真是个好主意  韩非说
“Let’s go back to the school and get some water.”
我们回学校取点水吧
Soon they get some water and pour it into the hole, and the ball comes up.
不久他们拿来了水倒进洞里  球浮了上来
“Now we can get the ball,” says Han Fei.
现在我们可以拿到球了  韩非说道
She takes the ball out and gives it to the boy.
她把球拿出来给了那个男孩
The boy smiles and says, “Thank you very much.”
男孩笑着说  太感谢你们了